Guide to the Bob Long Collection, 1936-1944, 1991
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Bob Long collection 1936-1944, 1991
University Archives, Duke University
Long, Robert F.
0.5 Linear Feet About 150 Items
Bob Long was a 1941 graduate of Duke University.
Collection contains photographs, clippings, Duke ephemera, and printed matter such as handbooks and programs. The collection ranges in date from 1936-1944, 1991.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Bob Long Collection were received by the University Archives as a gift in 1994 and 1995.
Biographical Note
Bob Long, a native of Baltimore, Maryland, was a 1941 graduate of Duke University. He was a member of the Chanticleer staff for all four of his years at Duke and served as business manager during his senior year. Long was also a member of Omicron Delta Kappa, Phi Delta Theta, Beta Omega Sigma, and Tombs. Additionally, Long was a member of the track, cross-country, and lacrosse teams.
Collection Overview
Collection contains photographs which document student life in the late 1930s and early 1940s. Subjects include athletics, commencement, social activities and societal events. Of particular note are photographs from an unidentified student event where subjects are in blackface. The collection also contains various printed matter, including handbooks and programs, and Duke ephemera, including Duke Alumni window decals and paper pennants. The collection ranges in date from 1936-1944, 1991.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Long, Robert F.
Duke University -- Alumni and alumnae
Duke University -- Sports
Duke University -- Students -- Social life and customs
Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc
Separated Material
1938 Commemorative football towel and undated sign which says "Please keep off the grass" in French were placed in Artifacts and Relics Collection (see finding aid).
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Photographs, circa 1937-1944 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1940, undated
  - Rose Bowl program and magazine, 1939
  - Southern Conference Track Championships program, 1938 May
  - The Duke Phi newsletter, 1944 November
  - Woman's College handbook, 1935/1936, 1937/1938
  - Omicron of Alpha Delta Pi: Silver Jubilee, 1911-1936, 1936
  - Duke Ephemera, undated
  - Commencement Programs, 1939
  - Christmas Card, 1991